<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jacky zhao | blog</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on jacky zhao | blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 13:43:34 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jzhao.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2020: An Imperfect Palindrome</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/2020-an-imperfect-palindrome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 13:43:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/2020-an-imperfect-palindrome/</guid><description>A year of &amp;lsquo;almosts&amp;rsquo; 2020 is:
about 9.5 times longer than a Rick Roll in seconds about 54 times longer than the number of minutes I listened to Spotify this year about how many contributions I made on GitHub this year roughly the amount of pages I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year almost a palindrome Now there&amp;rsquo;s nothing super fascinating about almost-palindromes but it is also very fitting given the number of &amp;lsquo;almosts&amp;rsquo; in my year.</description></item><item><title>Collaborative Thinking</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/collaborative-thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 13:44:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/collaborative-thinking/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading 21 Lessons for the 21st Century written by none other than Yuval Noah Harari, and have been enjoying the book. Its approach to weaving together insights from a vast number of disciplines to create something novel is extremely refreshing. I just read a section on learning, the knowledge illusion, and collaborative thinking and wanted to share some of my thoughts that have been bouncing around and marinating for a few days as well as some learnings that I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to my own life.</description></item><item><title>Machines and Intelligence</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/machines-and-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:17:37 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/machines-and-intelligence/</guid><description>This blog post is adapted from a term paper I wrote for PHIL250: Minds and Machines at UBC. I hope you enjoy the post and learn as much as I did in writing it!
Introduction Historically, development of AI has taken a very specific approach — systems that represent the world through symbols and manipulate those tokens in a systematic way to arrive at a result. This type of AI was coined Good Old-Fashioned AI (GOFAI) by John Haugeland1.</description></item><item><title>On AI’s ‘bias bug’</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/bias-bug/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 16:27:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/bias-bug/</guid><description>This blog post was originally intended to be a TED Talk given at TEDxRedmond but I unfortunately was never accepted. However, I did learn a lot in the process of writing it, and I hope you get some value out of it even its presented through just text.
Hey Google, Take a picture in 5 seconds. Say cheese!
See that? This is just one of many examples of where AI is becoming a larger part of what we accept as normal.</description></item><item><title>A Failure Resume</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/a-failure-resume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 14:02:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/a-failure-resume/</guid><description>Imposter Syndrome has been hitting really hard lately. Sometimes, it makes me feel like I don&amp;rsquo;t deserve a lot of my current accomplishments and that I need to work even harder just to feel like I deserve what I have right now. I came across the concept of a failure resume1 a while ago, a list of things that didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly go according to plan, and the lessons learned.
The more I think about it, the more I realize that a failure resume is a great way to document all the spectacular ways you&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard towards your own goals and accomplishments, validating them in a sense.</description></item><item><title>Docker Explained</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/docker-explained/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:14:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/docker-explained/</guid><description>Content from my own &amp;lsquo;Docker Explained&amp;rsquo; repo. Check out the repository for example code!
Table of Contents 👋Introduction What is Docker? What are containers? Why containers? Why Docker? 🔨Installing Docker ⚙️Parts of Docker Docker Containers Docker Image Layers Dockerfile Docker CLI 📝Docker Examples 📚Further reading Docker Compose Kubernetes and Microservices Deploying to the Cloud Closing 👋 Introduction What is Docker?</description></item><item><title>reflect: NLP model explained pt.1</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/reflect-nlp-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 08:51:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/reflect-nlp-1/</guid><description>How do we tell that this is a “valid” intent?
A (not so) brief exploration of how we tackle classifying intents in reflect. Part 1 will touch on defining the problem we’re trying to solve, the data we have, and how we pre-processed it. Part 2 will focus on the architecture of the model we built, how well it does, and thoughts on improving it for the future.
The problem Classifying intents is at the core of reflect.</description></item><item><title>reflect: NLP model explained pt.2</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/reflect-nlp-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 08:51:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/reflect-nlp-2/</guid><description>How do we tell that this is a “valid” intent?
In this second part, we’ll take a deep dive into the neural network that helps us solve this hefty problem of classifying whether an intent is valid or not.
Recall that in part 1, we went over the data we had, and how we could prepare that data to feed into our neural network. Now that we have all our data ready and prepped, let’s talk about the model!</description></item><item><title>Life of a High School SWE Intern at Hootsuite</title><link>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/hootsuite-hs-intern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 08:51:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jzhao.xyz/posts/hootsuite-hs-intern/</guid><description>(with insights from Calvin and Hobbes)
Since I’ve started at Hootsuite, I have
added and/or changed 6223 lines of code in 16 different repos
closed 24 tickets
made 4 new Slack emotes
listened to almost 10,000 minutes of lofi
had 1 amazing summer at Hootsuite
Including the amount of money I’ve spent on lunch this past summer, everything has been so much more than I expected it to be.</description></item></channel></rss>